[upbeat ukulele music]
[欢快的尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
Nice work, boy-o.
干得好，小伙子。
She looks cleaner than
a freshly scraped hull.
她看起来比
刚刮过的船体
Oh, hello, Mr. Krabs, I...
[gasps]
哦，你好，蟹老板，我...
[喘气]
Your feet!
你的脚！
Hmm?
唔？
[shivering]
[发抖]
Whew!
That was close.
哇！
那很接近了。
You almost tracked goo all over
your nice, clean restaurant.
你几乎浑身都沾满了粘液
你漂亮、干净的餐厅。
[chuckles]
Good save, huh?
[笑声]
保存得很好吧？
[groans]
[呻吟]
Huh?
啊？
Hmm...
唔...
Oh, looks like this puddle here
is the culprit.
哦，看起来像这里的水坑
是罪魁祸首。
Don't worry, Mr. K.,
别担心，K先生，
I'll have her cleaned up
in no time.
我会让她清理干净
很快。
Hmm...
Aha!
嗯...
啊哈！
[engine turning over, revving]
[发动机转动、加速]
[gargling]
[漱口]
Okay, you just pour this
in here, and...
好的，你只要倒这个
在这里，还有……
Huh?
[screams]
啊？
[尖叫声]
"It's a beautiful day,"
you said.
“这是美好的一天，”
你说。
"Why not do some evil science
outside?" you said.
“为什么不做一些邪恶的科学呢？
外面？”你说。
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
What in Neptune's navel
are you doing?
海王星的肚脐里有什么
你在做什么？
Oh, sorry, Plankton.
哦，对不起，浮游生物。
I was just cleaning up
this goo puddle for Mr. Krabs.
我刚刚打扫卫生
这个粘糊糊的水坑是给蟹老板的。
That doesn't look like goo.
这看起来不太像。
It looks like oil.
看起来像油。
Holy moly, Karen!
天啊，凯伦！
We're sittin'
on a mountain of moolah!
我们坐着
在金钱之山上！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
That oil's mine, you hear?
那油是我的，听到了吗？
My employee found it,
and besides,
我的员工发现了，
除此之外，
it's on me property!
这是我的财产！
Not so fast, Krabs.
没那么快，蟹蟹。
That's my oil,
这是我的油
and it's on my property!
这是我的财产！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
[both growl]
[双方咆哮]
Mmm.
Actually, you're both wrong.
嗯。
事实上，你们都错了。
It's not oil at all.
它根本不是油。
both: It's not?
两人：不是吗？
According to my analysis,
根据我的分析，
it's a combination
of Krabby Patty grease
这是一个组合
蟹黄饼油脂
and Chum runoff,
和密姆径流，
which your two restaurants
have been leaking
你们的两家餐厅是哪一家
已经泄漏
into the ground for decades.
埋入地下数十年。
So it's just
worthless old grease?
所以这只是
旧油脂毫无价值？
I wouldn't call it
"worthless."
我不会这么称呼它
“一文不值。”
It has a high viscosity index
它具有高粘度指数
and impressive flavor-imparting
characteristics.
以及令人印象深刻的风味
特点。
So its "worthful"?
那么它“值得”吗？
Yes, however,
是的，但是，
the deposit appears to be
evenly split
押金似乎是
均分
between your restaurants.
您的餐厅之间。
Well, Plankton, looks like
嗯，浮游生物，看起来像
if we want to make
a lot of money...
如果我们想做
很多钱...
We'll have to do it as...
我们必须这样做...
[groans]
both: Partners.
[呻吟]
两者：伙伴。
Come on, Krabs.
来吧，蟹蟹们。
There's got to be some use
for this stuff we can agree on.
总得有点用处
对于这些事情我们可以达成一致。
Mm, let's sell it
to the military!
嗯嗯，卖掉吧
到军队！
Imagine...
fuel for flamethrowers,
想象一下...
火焰喷射器的燃料，
lubricant for killer robots,
杀手机器人的润滑剂，
bombs that smell
like French fries!
有气味的炸弹
就像炸薯条一样！
[laughs]
[笑]
all: Mmm.
全体：嗯。
We'll use it to boost
business at The Krusty Krab...
我们将用它来增强
蟹堡王 (Krusty Krab) 的生意...
a flavorful new sandwich topping
美味的新三明治配料
a savory new milkshake,
美味的新奶昔，
and a lovely new scent
for the restrooms.
还有可爱的新香味
用于洗手间。
[all sniffing]
[大家都在嗅闻]
Oh, no!
哦，不！
We're not using my grease
to drive customers
我们没有使用我的油脂
带动客户
to your restaurant!
到你的餐厅！
- Oh, you...
- Why, I ought to...
- 哦，你...
- 为什么，我应该...
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
Oh, gosh, I don't see why
you need to find just one use
哦，天哪，我不明白为什么
你只需要找到一种用途
for this stuff.
对于这个东西。
I started using it
for everything.
我开始使用它
对于一切。
- What?
- Huh?
- 什么？
- 啊？
Toothpaste,
牙膏，
bodywash, deodorant,
沐浴露、除臭剂
shoe polish,
鞋油，
all-night face mask,
整夜面膜，
Gary's breakfast,
加里的早餐，
my own breakfast.
我自己的早餐。
It even cured my bursitis!
它甚至治愈了我的滑囊炎！
What I mean is,
我的意思是，
if you can use it for anything,
如果你能用它来做任何事
why not sell it for everything?
为什么不把它全部卖掉呢？
[cash register bell dings]
[收银机铃响]
[cash register bell dings,
horn toots]
[收银机铃声响起，
喇叭嘟嘟声]
Not bad.
不错。
Well, we better get some
customers here, Eugene.
好吧，我们最好买一些
这里的顾客，尤金。
I was up all night
painting that sign.
我整夜没睡
画那个标志。
Have a little faith, Plankton.
要有一点信心，浮游生物。
[gasps]
[喘气]
Behold, the lunch rush!
看哪，午餐高峰期！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[both scream]
[两人尖叫]
Whoa!
哇！
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
Time to get to work!
- [laughs]
是时候去上班了！
- [笑]
[babies crying]
[婴儿哭声]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Pardon me, ma'am,
but how about some
请原谅我，女士，
但一些怎么样
Dr. Krabton's Miracle
Everything Juice
克拉布顿博士的奇迹
一切果汁
to quiet the little angels?
[grunts]
让小天使安静下来？
[咕哝]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[grunts]
Hmm...
[咕哝]
嗯...
[groans]
[呻吟]
why, Dr. Krabton
can fix up your boat for you!
为什么，克拉布顿博士
可以为您修理您的船！
See?
看？
There you go.
Good as new.
就这样吧。
完好如新。
Say, it really works!
说吧，确实有效！
Three cheers
for Everything Juice!
三声欢呼
一切果汁！
all: Hooray!
全体：万岁！
[indistinct chatter]
- We'll take one!
[模糊的喋喋不休]
- 我们要一个！
[excited chatter]
[兴奋的喋喋不休]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Look at all this cash, Krabs!
看看这么多现金，蟹蟹们！
We're rich!
- Not rich enough.
我们有钱了！
- 不够富有。
We got to take our show
on the road!
我们必须参加我们的表演
在路上！
[boat beeping]
[船的嘟嘟声]
All right, Plankton.
好吧，浮游生物。
Let a real salesman show you
how it's done.
让真正的推销员告诉你
它是如何完成的。
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
Eugene?
What a surprise.
尤金？
真是一个惊喜。
Uh, we don't have
a lunch date today, do we?
呃，我们没有
今天有一个午餐约会，可以吗？
Not with me.
Your date today is with value.
不和我在一起。
你今天的约会很有价值。
Suppose I told you
there was one product
假设我告诉你
有一种产品
that could fuel
all your boats...
这可以燃料
你所有的船...
[engines rev]
Reinvigorate
[发动机转速]
重振活力
old lighthouse paint jobs...
- [grunts]
旧灯塔油漆工作...
- [咕哝]
And even cover up those...
[clears throat]
甚至掩盖那些...
[清嗓子]
Maturation lines
around your eyes.
成熟线
你的眼睛周围。
Plank.
板。
♪ ♪
♪♪
How dare you?
你怎么敢？
Give me ten bottles.
给我十瓶。
You did pretty good
back there, Krabs.
你做得很好
回到那里，蟹蟹。
But now it's time
to watch a master!
但现在是时候了
来围观高手！
Ooh, gladly.
[doorbell rings]
哦，很高兴。
[门铃响]
Let me know when he gets here.
[laughs]
当他到达这里时请告诉我。
[笑]
- Howdy.
- Greetings, Sandra.
- 你好。
- 你好，桑德拉。
I am here to tell you
about our latest invention.
我来这里是为了告诉你
关于我们的最新发明。
It'll fertilize your lawn.
它会给你的草坪施肥。
[grunts goofily]
[愚蠢地咕哝]
Polish your dome glass...
擦亮你的圆顶玻璃...
Oh.
哦。
[hums]
- [chirping]
[哼哼]
- [叽叽喳喳]
And give even your oldest
nuts that fresh-picked shine!
甚至给你最年长的
新鲜采摘的坚果闪闪发光！
[snickers]
[窃笑]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
It's Dr. Krabton's
Miracle Everything Juice!
这是克拉布顿博士的
奇迹一切果汁！
[fanfare plays]
[吹奏乐曲]
I ain't some hayseed, Plankton.
我不是干草籽，浮游生物。
I'm a scientist.
我是一名科学家。
I don't believe in miracles.
我不相信奇迹。
Well, but it can also keep
oxygen machines running
嗯，不过还可以保留
制氧机运行
in top shape!
处于最佳状态！
Huh...
呃……
[machine wheezing and coughing]
[机器喘息和咳嗽]
Well, I do like breathin'.
嗯，我确实喜欢呼吸。
I'll take a whole case!
我要接整个案子！
This door-to-door stuff's
taking too long.
这种挨家挨户的事情
花了太长时间。
We got to go big!
- How big?
我们必须做大！
- 有多大？
Musical big!
音乐剧大！
[upbeat music plays]
[欢快的音乐响起]
♪ ♪
[crowd oohing]
[人群欢呼]
♪ Hey, there, mister,
would you like to know ♪
♪ 嘿，先生，
你想知道吗♪
♪ About a very
a special something ♪
♪ 关于一个非常
特别的东西♪
♪ That makes
all your problems go away? ♪
♪ 这使得
你所有的问题都消失了吗？ ♪
What is it?
它是什么？
- It's Everything Juice.
- What?
- 一切都是果汁。
- 什么？
♪ Hey, there, madam,
can I help you out ♪
♪ 嘿，女士，
我可以帮你吗 ♪
♪ With those
false teeth of yours ♪
♪ 与那些
你的假牙♪
♪ It must be very hard
to shout hooray ♪
♪ 一定很难
欢呼万岁♪
- [screams]
- ♪ For Everything Juice ♪
- [尖叫]
- ♪ 一切果汁 ♪
♪ Can it make my voice
sound much more creepy? ♪
♪ 它能发出我的声音吗
听起来更令人毛骨悚然？ ♪
- Probably.
- ♪ Will it fix the smell ♪
- 大概。
- ♪ 它能消除气味吗 ♪
♪ Of my pet Kiki? ♪
♪ 我的宠物琪琪？ ♪
- Buy it and see!
- Indeed!
- 买来看看！
- 的确！
♪ Hey, there, son,
looks like you might need ♪
♪ 嘿，儿子，
看起来你可能需要 ♪
♪ To find some
slickening solution ♪
♪ 寻找一些
光滑液♪
♪ So your marbles
can get up to speed today ♪
♪ 所以你的弹珠
今天可以跟上进度了♪
Try Everything Juice!
尝试一切果汁！
♪ Pardon me,
but I see you chose ♪
♪ 请原谅我，
但我看到你选择了♪
♪ Not to trim that
rather lengthy hair ♪
♪ 不要修剪它
头发比较长♪
♪ Protruding from your nose,
but that's okay ♪
♪ 从你的鼻子里伸出来，
但没关系♪
With Everything Juice!
一切果汁！
- How much does it cost?
- Quite a lot!
- 它要多少钱？
- 相当多！
[cash register bell dings]
- I don't care.
[收银机铃响]
- 我不在乎。
Give me everything you've got.
把你拥有的一切都给我。
both: ♪ Yes, my friends,
this is the greatest stuff ♪
两人：♪ 是的，我的朋友们，
这是最伟大的东西♪
♪ It's a wonder,
it's a miracle ♪
♪ 这是一个奇迹，
这是一个奇迹♪
♪ You just can't have enough ♪
♪ 你就是不够 ♪
♪ So we say hey ♪
♪ 所以我们说嘿 ♪
♪ Get some today ♪
♪ 今天就买一些 ♪
♪ There's no excuse ♪
♪ 没有任何借口 ♪
♪ Everyone needs
Everything Juice ♪
♪ 每个人都需要
一切都是果汁♪
[crowd clamoring]
[人群喧闹]
[cash register bell dings]
[收银机铃响]
A million one, a million two,
一百万一，一百万二，
a million three.
一百万三。
Eugene, is this what
friendship feels like?
尤金，这是什么？
友谊是什么样的感觉？
Perhaps it is, Sheldon.
Perhaps it is.
也许是的，谢尔顿。
也许是的。
both: Money fight!
[giggling]
两人：金钱战！
[咯咯笑]
[elevator bell dings]
- Huh?
[电梯铃声]
- 啊？
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
Hey!
What are you all doing in here?
嘿！
你们都在这里做什么？
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
We are unsatisfied customers!
我们是不满意的顾客！
Just look at what your grease
did to my air!
看看你的油脂是什么
对我的空气做了什么！
[yelling continues]
[喊叫继续]
all: Ew.
所有人：呃。
Your grease gave me pink eye!
你的油脂让我红了眼睛！
Well, at least your...
[clears throat]
好吧，至少你的...
[清嗓子]
Maturation lines are gone.
成熟线消失了。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
I'll take two more bottles.
我再拿两瓶。
No more!
不再！
You two have ruined
the whole town!
你们两个毁了
整个城镇！
all: We want our money back!
全体：我们要回我们的钱！
Huh?
[chuckles nervously]
啊？
[紧张地笑]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
[sighs]
I knew you would mess this up.
[叹气]
我就知道你会把事情搞砸的。
You always mess things up.
你总是把事情搞砸。
Me?
我？
I'm not the one who came up
with that lousy song.
我不是上来的人
和那首糟糕的歌。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[pump wheezes]
[泵喘息声]
Must be running low on grease.
一定是油脂不足了。
Oh, well, it wasn't me
who sold it
哦，好吧，那不是我
谁卖的
as fire extinguisher
recharging fluid.
作为灭火器
充电液。
All right, all right.
好吧，好吧。
But I'm not the one who sold it
但我不是卖它的人
as acne treatment
to high schoolers.
作为痤疮治疗
给高中生。
Oh, but you did market it
as drinkable vitamins!
哦，但你确实推销过它
作为可饮用的维生素！
That's it!
就是这样！
This friendship is over!
这段友谊就结束了！
We are mortal enemies once more!
我们又是不共戴天的敌人了！
Fine by me!
对我来说很好！
I don't want to see you
ever again, ever!
我不想见你
再来一次，永远！
[doors slam]
[关上门]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
Whoa, whoa.
[screams]
哇哦，哇哦。
[尖叫声]
[groans]
[呻吟]
This is all your fault!
这都是你的错！
You trapped us in here!
你把我们困在这里了！
Oh, I wish I'd never met you!
哦，我希望我从未遇见过你！
That goes double for me!
这对我来说是双倍的！
Oh, boy!
哦，孩子！
The three best friends
buried alive together forever,
三个最好的朋友
永远活埋在一起，
and it's all thanks to...
而这一切都归功于...
♪ Everything Juice ♪
♪ 一切果汁 ♪